Mehrdad Qasemkhani

Tehran, Iran



gasemkhani.mehrdad@gmail.com



+989385200818



linkedin.com/in/gasemkhani-mehrdad

Summary

Experienced DevOps Engineer high focus on Kubernetes Cluster, with a demonstrated history of working in the cloud internet telephony industry. Skilled in SQL and noSQL Databases, like Mysql, Postgres, Apache ChouchDB, Functional and Object-Oriented Programming, like Erlang, Java and Python. Linux and ShellScripting. DevOps tools, like Git, CI/CD, Docker, Ansible. VoIP tools, like Kamailio, Asterisk, Freeswitch. Some TCP/IP protocol like HTTP, HTTPS, SIP, RTP, SDP, NAT, IP, ARP, TCP, UDP. Strong engineering professional graduated from Shamsipour and Raja university.

Experience



DevOps Architect

Fanavaran Hooshmand Behsazan Farda (Holding)

Sep 2020 - Present (4 months +)

- Kubernetes Architecture in Cluster and Auto Scale Mode
- Monitoring all Products with Prometheus Stack
- Deploy own Source Version Control(gitlab)

DevOps Engineer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Feb 2020 - Sep 2020 (8 months)

- Cloud Telecommunication Technology CPaaS, UCaaS
- Session Initiation Protocol
- Kamailio SIP-Server
- Asterisk/Freeswitch Softswitch
- Maintainer of own SIP-Trunk
- Maintainer of own Cloud HostedPBX
- SIP/HTTP Load Balancing
- High Availability
- Virtual Router Redundancy Protocol
- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with Python and Django
- Develop Asterisk Call App Manager Over The ARI with pure Python
- Automate all deploying process with CI/CD
- Automate configuration management, and application-deployment via Ansible

Backend Developer

Respina Networks & Beyond

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 (9 months)

Develop ARI(Asterisk RESTful Interface) with python and Django

• Develop Asterisk Call Manager Over The ARI with pure python

Python Developer

Kara Tadbir Hooshmand Kish

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

- Analyzed, designed and developed of a RESTful API with Python, Flask, gREST and Neo4j, PostgreSQL, Kong, ... to serve 2.5 million subscribers
- Experienced with pair-programming of project with junior/senior developers
- Hands-on experience with many of the latest cutting-edge technologies
- Provided regular and effective progress updates to my-head
- Write some python's unit-test and integration-test to develop CI/CD

C Developer

AVA Communication Industries Co.

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017 (5 months)

As a fresh graduated programmer we were developing some application and tools over the SIP protocol(Session Initiation Protocol). I wrote some part of these project with C and JS high focus on websocket progtamming.

Education



Shamsipour Technical and Vocational College

Associate's Degree, Copmuter 2009 - 2011



Bachelor of Science (BS) 2011 - 2013

Skills

Voice over IP (VoIP) • DevOps • Programming • High Availability • OOP • Algorithms • Software Development • Data Structures • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Linux System Administration